<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Democracy | Hugo Academic CV Theme</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/tags/democracy/</link><atom:link href="https://yukosato.github.io/tags/democracy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Democracy</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:05:08 +0900</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://yukosato.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url><title>Democracy</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/tags/democracy/</link></image><item><title>Crisis of Democracy?: Targeted Protest and Affective Polarization</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/book/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:05:08 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://yukosato.github.io/book/</guid><description>&lt;p>My book manuscript, &lt;em>Crisis of Democracy?: Targeted Protest and Affective Polarization&lt;/em>, systematically examines the consequences of protests on the stability of democracy. My central argument is that protests serve as focal events that may reshape voters’ political perceptions. I seek to expand the social identity theory to mass polarization by theorizing and testing how political protests may enhance individual partisan identities. Political protests provide the public with open information containing a specific political message about targeted candidates or parties. Accordingly, exposure to protests may activate pre-existing sympathy or antipathy toward the targeted group at the individual level and ultimately trigger affective polarization. To test this argument, I utilize a range of quantitative analyses, including time-series and cross-national studies and survey analysis with a natural experiment. I also triangulate quantitative methods with qualitative data gathered during my fieldwork in Brazil. The findings have implications for understanding the impact of protests on the polarization process and destabilization of democracy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Delegating away Democracy?: Martial Law Support in South Korea (Under Review)</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/project/martial_law/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:05:08 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://yukosato.github.io/project/martial_law/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why do citizens sometimes accept undemocratic actions by political leaders? Building on growing debates about citizens&amp;rsquo; democratic attitudes, we argue that support for executive power grabs depends not only on citizens&amp;rsquo; partisan alignment but also on their perceptions of government performance and animosity toward political opponents. South Korea’s sudden declaration of martial law in December 2024 offers a unique real-world case to test this argument. Using original survey data collected one month after the incident from 1,500 respondents, we find that individuals with positive views of the economy, particularly incumbent supporters, are more likely to endorse martial law. Hostility toward the opposition further amplifies this support and weakens the link between economic evaluations and democratic accountability. Our findings suggest that even in established democracies, public support for democratic norms can erode rapidly in times of crisis&amp;mdash;especially under deep polarization and when citizens view the executive as effective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>State of the world 2022: defiance in the face of autocratization</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/publication/democratization4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 23:55:21 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://yukosato.github.io/publication/democratization4/</guid><description/></item><item><title>State of the World 2021: Autocratization Changing its Nature?</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/publication/democratization3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 23:55:21 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://yukosato.github.io/publication/democratization3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Determinants of Successful Participatory Institutions in Brazil</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/publication/latin_america-ronshu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 23:55:21 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://yukosato.github.io/publication/latin_america-ronshu/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>