<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Preprint | Yuko Sato</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/publication_types/preprint/</link><atom:link href="https://yukosato.github.io/publication_types/preprint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Preprint</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:05:08 +0900</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://yukosato.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url><title>Preprint</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/publication_types/preprint/</link></image><item><title>Delegating away Democracy?: Martial Law Support in South Korea (Under Review)</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/project/martial_law/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:05:08 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://yukosato.github.io/project/martial_law/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why do citizens sometimes accept undemocratic actions by political leaders? Building on growing debates about citizens&amp;rsquo; democratic attitudes, we argue that support for executive power grabs depends not only on citizens&amp;rsquo; partisan alignment but also on their perceptions of government performance and animosity toward political opponents. South Korea’s sudden declaration of martial law in December 2024 offers a unique real-world case to test this argument. Using original survey data collected one month after the incident from 1,500 respondents, we find that individuals with positive views of the economy, particularly incumbent supporters, are more likely to endorse martial law. Hostility toward the opposition further amplifies this support and weakens the link between economic evaluations and democratic accountability. Our findings suggest that even in established democracies, public support for democratic norms can erode rapidly in times of crisis&amp;mdash;especially under deep polarization and when citizens view the executive as effective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Targeted Protest and Affective Polarization (Under Review)</title><link>https://yukosato.github.io/project/affective_polarization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:05:08 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://yukosato.github.io/project/affective_polarization/</guid><description>&lt;p>Political protests increasingly play a critical role in shaping politics in democracies. What political consequences did the growing global protest cycle bring about within democratic countries with unrest? Drawing on social identity theory, I argue that protest events, which targeted specific parties or leaders, would serve as a focal event that enhances voters’ attachment to partisan identity. Targeted protests provide open information containing a specific political message about targeted candidates or parties to the public. Accordingly, exposure to protests may activate and reinforce pre-existing partisan identities and ultimately trigger affective polarization at the mass level. To examine this argument, I use cross-national survey data to test whether protests targeting ruling parties increased the level of mass polarization among 38 democracies between 1996 and 2021. The findings have implications for understanding the impact of protests on voting behavior and the process of polarization in democracies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>