<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Partisanship | Yuko Sato</title>
    <link>https://yukosato.github.io/tags/partisanship/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://yukosato.github.io/tags/partisanship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Partisanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:05:08 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://yukosato.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Partisanship</title>
      <link>https://yukosato.github.io/tags/partisanship/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegating away Democracy?: Martial Law Support in South Korea (Under Review)</title>
      <link>https://yukosato.github.io/project/martial_law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:05:08 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yukosato.github.io/project/martial_law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do citizens sometimes accept undemocratic actions by political leaders? Building on growing debates about citizens&amp;rsquo; democratic attitudes, we argue that support for executive power grabs depends not only on citizens&amp;rsquo; partisan alignment but also on their perceptions of government performance and animosity toward political opponents. South Korea’s sudden declaration of martial law in December 2024 offers a unique real-world case to test this argument. Using original survey data collected one month after the incident from 1,500 respondents, we find that individuals with positive views of the economy, particularly incumbent supporters, are more likely to endorse martial law. Hostility toward the opposition further amplifies this support and weakens the link between economic evaluations and democratic accountability. Our findings suggest that even in established democracies, public support for democratic norms can erode rapidly in times of crisis&amp;mdash;especially under deep polarization and when citizens view the executive as effective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
